<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia Tufts</title>
    <description>Julia Tufts personal site, mathematics, programming, piano, music, games, python, C#, Unity3d
</description>
    <link>http://juliatufts.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://juliatufts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 18:54:58 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 18:54:58 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going For a Random Walk in Processing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://natureofcode.com/&quot;&gt;The Nature of Code&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Shiffman recently; it’s a book about mathematical principles in the physical world and how to program natural systems using Processing. The very first example is to make a random walker class whose instantiation looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/RandomWalker0.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above random walker is represented by a single black pixel who randomly moves up, down, left or right with equal probability. I iterated on this example a few times: I first made the random walker into a 10x10 pixel square that changed color over time. In this version it’s easier to see the walker’s current movement and overall walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/RandomWalker.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I next made it so that the walker could only walk on squares it hadn’t already visited. This way, the canvas will fill up entirely with colored squares and then stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/RandomWalkerNoOverlap.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these beautifully moving walkers made me want to paint a river with them, so I did that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/RandomWalkerDefinedRegion.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I used multiple random walkers and made each a little less random by setting their probability of moving right to 0.5, moving up to 0.25, and moving down to 0.25. I hope you enjoy watching these as much as I do! I’ll continue to blog about my progress with &lt;a href=&quot;http://natureofcode.com/&quot;&gt;The Nature of Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/25/going-for-a-random-walk-in-processing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/25/going-for-a-random-walk-in-processing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting the Math Feel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is delightful satisfaction in experiencing a good math feel. This satisfaction is not only found in solving problems and proving theorems, it also resides in the most basic building blocks of mathematics. It’s a bit hard to describe the feeling that I’m talking about here, but I’ll try to give an easy-to-understand example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a person, let’s call them camper Cal, who needs a sleeping bag to survive a cold night in the woods. You’re given a special sleeping bag of mathematics that is adjustable in size, and you need to fit it for Cal. Now keep in mind that this person is a set size - you can’t squeeze them even a tiny bit to fit into a sleeping bag that’s smaller than them. Any sleeping bag bigger than Cal will hold them alright, but you don’t want to settle for just alright, you want to adjust the sleeping bag to have the perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section group&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag3.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;too small&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag4.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;alright&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag2.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;even better&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we require two things for our sleeping bag. We need our camper to fit inside it, i.e. it must be bigger than them. We also want our sleeping bag to be the closest fit of all the sleeping bags bigger than Cal. We could also state our sleeping bag criteria as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;it must be bigger than Cal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;it must be smaller than all other sleeping bags that are bigger than Cal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That second point may seem a bit convoluted at first, but it is equivalent to “being the closest fit”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section group&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag4.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag2.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag0.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me there are a few nice math feels going on here. One is the dual nature of finding the smallest bag of a collection of bags that are bigger than another rigid object. Like infinitely many sleeping bags expanding around a camper and then falling away as a single one with the closest fit remains. Another is thinking about this perfectly snug sleeping bag itself. That of all the bigger-than-Cal sleeping bags, it can fit inside all of them. That if it was even a hair smaller, it wouldn’t have room for Cal to fit. Like a perfectly fit camper container that clicks into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve just described is an analogue to something called the &lt;strong&gt;supremum&lt;/strong&gt; of a set. For a subset A of the real numbers (your general purpose numbers that include integers, decimals and pi), the supremum of A is the real number α that satisfies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;alpha; is an upper bound for A, meaning that for all x in A, &amp;alpha; &amp;ge; x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;for all upper bounds b for A, &amp;alpha; &amp;le; b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my main objectives in learning how to program is to have the ability to embed good math feels into the accessible medium of games and interactive computer entities. Math can be dynamic and engaging, and it’s totally worth experiencing that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/23/getting-the-math-feel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/23/getting-the-math-feel.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging In</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is the result of a mental vector field shift; the need to concretize my thoughts and create a presence with them has overpowered the uncertainess of me actually being able to do that. This uncertainess is not a lack of confidence in my own ability, but a tendency to get bogged down with the frustration of never being able to explain what’s going on in my head in a completely satisfactory way. My current working solution is to get whatever thoughts I’m having out there, no matter how messy or incomplete. I’ll be blogging about my progress as a programmer, what I’m learning, what I’m working on, ideas for future projects, concepts to explore, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will aim to not spend too much time obsessing over posts, making them eloquent, complete and well-ordered. My blog motto will be : periodic over perfection. I hope to gain a better understanding of my own thoughts by writing about them, and track the progres of my ideas. And I hope you like reading about what I have to say. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-08-22.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/22/blogging-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/08/22/blogging-in.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
