<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia Tufts</title>
    <description>Julia Tufts personal site, mathematics, programming, piano, music, games, python, C#, Unity3d
</description>
    <link>http://juliatufts.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://juliatufts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 20:52:30 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 20:52:30 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Square Rotation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Playing around with rotations, nested pushMatrix() / popMatrix() blocks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/SquareRotation.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overlapping squares come in two flavors: red/green/blue and yellow/cyan/magenta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/09/21/square-rotation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/09/21/square-rotation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>processing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indecision</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what I’d like to do in life. I’ve just scaled the cliff face of university to discover an overgrown jungle at the top. I have no idea what the best way to approach it is, so I try hacking my way through one path, have second thoughts and double back, then try hacking my way through another and another. Never really getting anywhere, and never figuring out what the right way to do it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do know that I would like to program. But what exactly? How do I figure that out? Should I go back to university? Should I try to find a job? I keep thinking around in circles, chopping at bits of that jungle once in a while but never making any real progess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to the conclusion that I’m not going to figure any of that out until I try a lot of things, write a lot of code, and undoubtedly make a lot of mistakes. The worst thing to do is get stuck and not do anything at all. I’m leaving for Hacker School in New York City in 12 days. I’m both excited and terrified to be thrown into the code cauldron, work on projects and meet new people with similar interests. I just need to find the self-direction to pick a thing and work hard at it, and not get held back by indecision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/09/20/indecision.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/09/20/indecision.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Checkerboard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reviewing transformations in Processing and made a sliding checkerboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/CheckerboardSlide.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the very first functions I wrote in Python was a checkerboard drawing function. Feeling all the nostalgia today friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 13:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/09/20/checkerboard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/09/20/checkerboard.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>processing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Light Gravity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Experimenting a little more with gravitational attraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/LightGravity.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a bunch of star lights represented by white dots that are attracted to invisible points in space. Click on the sketch to reset!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/LightGrid.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a bonus sketch where the star lights start on a grid and follow invisible attractors that rotate around the center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/19/light-gravity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/19/light-gravity.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Planets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading about gravitational attraction in the Nature of Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/GravitationalAttraction.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not completely satisfied with how the planets cross into the star sometimes, but at least I’m not in charge of designing our solar system amirite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 16:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/18/planets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/18/planets.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fluid Resistance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning about how to implement fluid resistance in the Nature of Code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/MoversDrag.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can click and drag on the ball to pick it up and drop it into water bins of varying resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/17/fluid-resistance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/17/fluid-resistance.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Birthday Devin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Devin is p f c. He is very intelligent, artistic, spirited, charismatic and has great style. He is one of the best programmers I know. Hangouts with Devin are adventures where you’re part of a super friend gang called the Chroma Luma Kids. They’re the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/DevinComp.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the Sketch and type stuff! It’s a bit jank, but I thought it best not to spend even more time manually adjusting rectangles to make it pixel perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/16/happy-birthday-devin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/16/happy-birthday-devin.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Friction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to Nature of Code, this time playing around with friction. The balls closer to the center of the screen have a lower coefficient of friction: this means that the friction force is less and so they move faster than the balls with a higher coefficient. The equation for &lt;b&gt;Friction&lt;/b&gt; (a vector) is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friction&lt;/b&gt; = -1 * c * N * &lt;b&gt;v&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where c is the coefficient of friction, N is the normal force, and &lt;b&gt;v&lt;/b&gt; is the velocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/MoversFriction.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about forces and friction reminds me of that Magic School Bus episode where they’re playing baseball on a field with coefficient of friction equal to 0. What a great episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/15/friction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/15/friction.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bezier Curves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to look more into Bezier curves, and try generating some with a sequence of points. I figured I could make a nice looking sine wave by joining two Bezier curves, the first with control points directly above the start and end points, and the second with control points below. This makes a nice pattern of start/end points and control points: the start/end points are always on a horizonal line, equally spaced and the control points are on another horizonal line, directly above or below them. Like dots on a grid. Then I linearly interpolate the control points from this starting position, to the next one in the pattern for the x-position, and increase the first control point’s y-position to make it stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/BezierJoyDivision.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press space to pause if you want to get a better look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/14/bezier-curves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/14/bezier-curves.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ball Pit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning more about forces, and bouncing things made me think about ball pits. And wanting to jump into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/BallPit.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting the bottom of the window adds a little extra bounce to the ball and sends it off to the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/13/ball-pit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/13/ball-pit.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
