<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:30:19 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:30:19 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meta Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to redo my website recently. It was nice to revisit a development process with a bunch of new knowledge and insight, and see how differently I approached it. It also gave me the chance to take a long hard look at the under-used moleskine journal that is my blog. That got me thinking about what sort of posts worked well, or didn’t, and why. So I decided to reflect a bit on that and try to get a better footing blogging forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let me point out a few reasons for writing a blog. These ones are ordered by how relevant they are to my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;You&#39;re learning about how to make a website that has a blog.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;You are learning/have learned about a thing, and would like to crystallize the knowledge of that thing. Explaining it in words is a good way to do that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;You have a thought or opinion on something that doesn&#39;t necessarily correspond to learning, but you don&#39;t want to forget about it. By investigating and analyzing it, and then writing about your findings, you can flesh out your idea, add reasoning to your opinion, and avoid letting those precious brain gems of yours fall into the void of lost memory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Intelligent people that you respect recommend that you write a blog, listing a variant of the reasons above, and/or some reasons of their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How To Blog Well?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What works well in a blog or not depends very much on the type of blog it is. In my case, I’m writing a small, low-effort blog on my personal website. At the moment I’m not expecting very many people to come across and read it, but I’m also aware that the possibility exists. In writing a blog, my biggest challenge is just getting the writing done and published itself. I have a tendency to be a perfectionist, spinning on drafts that never get finished. To overcome that, my main goal is to just simply write down more stuff that I am learning, or don’t want to forget. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the word “well” is hard to define. Here are some pictures describing what I mean in this context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img style=&quot;width: 100%; max-width: 400px;&quot; src=&quot;/blog/images/2016-09-24-meta-blog/posts_that_work_well.png&quot; alt=&quot;posts_that_work_well&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Posts that worked well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img style=&quot;width: 100%; max-width: 400px;&quot; src=&quot;/blog/images/2016-09-24-meta-blog/posts_that_do_not_work_well.png&quot; alt=&quot;posts_that_do_not_work_well&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Posts that did not work well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of that in mind, here’s a summary of my findings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What did work well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Having posts, rather than not having any posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Posts with a clearly defined topic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Posts with pictures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What did not work well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Posts that were too personal for my comfort level&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Posts that didn&#39;t focus on a topic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Posts that were too short and didn&#39;t contain much concrete information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best general advice I glean from this is to have a clearly defined topic before you start writing a post. A blog post doesn’t always need to be an essay, but should contain at least one or two useful bits of knowledge or insight. A blog with posts is usually better than a blog with no posts, so try not to be discouraged from writing. You always learn more from your output (even if it’s not your best work), than you do from the nonexistant.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2016/09/24/meta-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2016/09/24/meta-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Machine &lt;3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I made an animation in JavaScript. Just press the button to make it start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot; class=&quot;jscanvas&quot; width=&quot;512px&quot; height=&quot;550px&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
	&lt;script src=&quot;/js/machinelove.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/10/23/machine-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/10/23/machine-love.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New York Here I Come</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sitting in an airport waiting for a flight that will take me to New York City. And it still hasn’t sunk in that I will be spending the next three months learning and coding at Hacker School. I have a few ideas for projects I’d like to work on, but at the moment I’m feeling like getting a solid grounding in Python might be a good first step. I do want to make some games and graphics and visualization stuff. It is all very undecided and terrifying, but also exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/NewYork.png&quot; alt=&quot;Artistic Rendition of New York City&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main objective at the moment is to get focused on something. I’m afraid I’ve been terribly unsure about everything so far and keep jumping around as a result. Other objectives include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;blogging regularly (even if I cringe at my own writing sometimes)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;talk to people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;power through self-doubt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;make time to not stress about things or feel like I should be working&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
note (2016/07/15): Hacker School has since rebranded as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/&quot;&gt;The Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/10/02/new-york-here-i-come.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/10/02/new-york-here-i-come.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting the Math Feel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is delightful satisfaction in experiencing a good math feel. This satisfaction is not only found in solving problems and proving theorems, it also resides in the most basic building blocks of mathematics. It’s a bit hard to describe the feeling that I’m talking about here, but I’ll try to give an easy-to-understand example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a person, let’s call them camper Cal, who needs a sleeping bag to survive a cold night in the woods. You’re given a special sleeping bag of mathematics that is adjustable in size, and you need to fit it for Cal. Now keep in mind that this person is a set size - you can’t squeeze them even a tiny bit to fit into a sleeping bag that’s smaller than them. Any sleeping bag bigger than Cal will hold them alright, but you don’t want to settle for just alright, you want to adjust the sleeping bag to have the perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section group&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag3.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;too small&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag4.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;alright&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag2.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;h4&gt;even better&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we require two things for our sleeping bag. We need our camper to fit inside it, i.e. it must be bigger than them. We also want our sleeping bag to be the closest fit of all the sleeping bags bigger than Cal. We could also state our sleeping bag criteria as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;it must be bigger than Cal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;it must be smaller than all other sleeping bags that are bigger than Cal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That second point may seem a bit convoluted at first, but it is equivalent to “being the closest fit”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section group&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag4.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag2.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col span_1_of_3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-23-sleeping-bag0.png&quot; id=&quot;outline&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me there are a few nice math feels going on here. One is the dual nature of finding the smallest bag of a collection of bags that are bigger than another rigid object. Like infinitely many sleeping bags expanding around a camper and then falling away as a single one with the closest fit remains. Another is thinking about this perfectly snug sleeping bag itself. That of all the bigger-than-Cal sleeping bags, it can fit inside all of them. That if it was even a hair smaller, it wouldn’t have room for Cal to fit. Like a perfectly fit camper container that clicks into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve just described is an analogue to something called the &lt;strong&gt;supremum&lt;/strong&gt; of a set. For a subset A of the real numbers (your general purpose numbers that include integers, decimals and pi), the supremum of A is the real number α that satisfies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;alpha; is an upper bound for A, meaning that for all x in A, &amp;alpha; &amp;ge; x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;for all upper bounds b for A, &amp;alpha; &amp;le; b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my main objectives in learning how to program is to have the ability to embed good math feels into the accessible medium of games and interactive computer entities. Math can be dynamic and engaging, and it’s totally worth experiencing that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/08/23/getting-the-math-feel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/08/23/getting-the-math-feel.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging In</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is the result of a mental vector field shift; the need to concretize my thoughts and create a presence with them has overpowered the uncertainess of me actually being able to do that. This uncertainess is not a lack of confidence in my own ability, but a tendency to get bogged down with the frustration of never being able to explain what’s going on in my head in a completely satisfactory way. My current working solution is to get whatever thoughts I’m having out there, no matter how messy or incomplete. I’ll be blogging about my progress as a programmer, what I’m learning, what I’m working on, ideas for future projects, concepts to explore, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will aim to not spend too much time obsessing over posts, making them eloquent, complete and well-ordered. My blog motto will be : periodic over perfection. I hope to gain a better understanding of my own thoughts by writing about them, and track the progres of my ideas. And I hope you like reading about what I have to say. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2014-08-22.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/08/22/blogging-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2014/08/22/blogging-in.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
