<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia Tufts</title>
    <description>Julia Tufts personal site, mathematics, programming, piano, music, games, python, C#, Unity3d
</description>
    <link>http://juliatufts.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://juliatufts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:15:19 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:15:19 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fluid Resistance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning about how to implement fluid resistance in the Nature of Code. You can click and drag on the ball to pick it up and drop it into water bins of varying resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/MoversDrag.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/17/fluid-resistance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/17/fluid-resistance.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Birthday Devin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Devin is p f c. He is very intelligent, artistic, spirited, charismatic and has great style. He is one of the best programmers I know. Hangouts with Devin are adventures where you’re part of a super friend gang called the Chroma Luma Kids. They’re the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/DevinComp.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the Sketch and type stuff! It’s a bit jank, but I thought it best not to spend even more time manually adjusting rectangles to make it pixel perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/16/happy-birthday-devin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/16/happy-birthday-devin.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Friction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to Nature of Code, this time playing around with friction. The balls closer to the center of the screen have a lower coefficient of friction: this means that the friction force is less and so they move faster than the balls with a higher coefficient. The equation for &lt;b&gt;Friction&lt;/b&gt; (a vector) is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friction&lt;/b&gt; = -1 * c * N * &lt;b&gt;v&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where c is the coefficient of friction, N is the normal force, and &lt;b&gt;v&lt;/b&gt; is the velocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/MoversFriction.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about forces and friction reminds me of that Magic School Bus episode where they’re playing baseball on a field with coefficient of friction equal to 0. What a great episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/15/friction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/15/friction.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bezier Curves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to look more into Bezier curves, and try generating some with a sequence of points. I figured I could make a nice looking sine wave by joining two Bezier curves, the first with control points directly above the start and end points, and the second with control points below. This makes a nice pattern of start/end points and control points: the start/end points are always on a horizonal line, equally spaced and the control points are on another horizonal line, directly above or below them. Like dots on a grid. Then I linearly interpolate the control points from this starting position, to the next one in the pattern for the x-position, and increase the first control point’s y-position to make it stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/BezierJoyDivision.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press space to pause if you want to get a better look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/14/bezier-curves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/14/bezier-curves.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ball Pit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning more about forces, and bouncing things made me think about ball pits. And wanting to jump into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/BallPit.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting the bottom of the window adds a little extra bounce to the ball and sends it off to the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/13/ball-pit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/13/ball-pit.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Balloons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More forces with a little foray into Bezier curves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/Balloons.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned from a friend that helium is mined. I think that’s pretty neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/12/balloons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/12/balloons.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leaves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading about forces with movement. Here is gravity and wind making some leaves move. Press space to apply more wind force!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/LeafForce.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I didn’t work in wind resistance yet, so these forces accumulate pretty fast and cause quite the whirlwind. But you can always press enter to reset :]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/11/leaves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/11/leaves.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not the Bees</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Playing around with random acceleration to get a jitter effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/Bees.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These bees accelerate towards the hive with a slightly random value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 14:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/10/not-the-bees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/10/not-the-bees.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colorful Attraction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Playing around with movement, and objects accelerating towards the mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/AccelerationTowardsMouse.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The color puffs move towards the mouse with varying top speed, depending on their size. The smaller ones tend to move more slowly than the larger ones. Notice how this allows them to get closer to the mouse cursor. You may also notice that the color opacity increases, the closer the puffs are to the mouse. I like the idea of gravitational forces, and having a colorful indicator of how compact things are; Sort of like you’re charging a super power!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 13:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/09/colorful-attraction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/09/colorful-attraction.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meteors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More movement with acceleration. This is how the dinosaurs died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/MeteorShower.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press space to reset the meteors. Things I learned from the making of this sketch: if details are taking too long to make, don’t obsess about it; You can make nicer looking randomly generated clouds some other day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post a Processing sketch every day for 100 days]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 11:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/08/meteors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/2014/09/08/meteors.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
