<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia Tufts</title>
    <description>Julia Tufts personal site, mathematics, programming, piano, music, games, python, C#, Unity3d
</description>
    <link>http://juliatufts.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://juliatufts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 11:16:07 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 11:16:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Birthday Rob</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Rob is super great. He’s intelligent, funny and caring; he makes terrific puns and is a wildly-fast learning and skilled programmer. Anyways, it’s his birthday today so I made him a thing that’s at the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;display: inline; padding: 5px&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/robot_butler.html&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;...&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/12/08/happy-birthday-rob.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/12/08/happy-birthday-rob.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 14</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I made an animation in JavaScript. Just press the button to make it start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot; class=&quot;jscanvas&quot; width=&quot;512px&quot; height=&quot;550px&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;/Scripts/machinelove.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/23/hacker-school-day-14.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/23/hacker-school-day-14.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 12</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the current agenda is JavaScript, Elm and Algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started writing a small JavaScript game based on graph coloring. Today I talked to Mary about it, having set up the basic game objects but not sure how to proceed with handling user input. Somehow we got to talking about the global object, how the &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; keyword behaves, how to use the arguments keyword properly, and how to make partial application functions. I’m still reading up about these and have yet to review the example code we went through together, but I definitely have a better sense of what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Elm music visualizer with Tanoy is coming along. The next step is incorporating audio, so I’ve started reading about how to do that with the JavaScript Web Audio API, so that we can port it to Elm as a Signal later (hopefully). Did I mention that Tanoy convinced me that we should present at last weeks demo Thursday event? Because he did and we presented a quick introduction to reactive graphics in Elm, ending with our current music visualization work. And I didn’t die, so I consider my first foray into public speaking at Hacker School a success. (I give credit to Tanoy and his effective “practice your presentation 5 times before you actually go and do it” method)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started a Coursera Algorithms course. I’m not sure how carefully I’ll actually follow through with it, but at the very least I’ll be watching the video lectures and trying to implement the algorithms presented in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue with Elm Music Visualizer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue with JavaScript Graph Game&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue with Algorithms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Read about D3.js, three.js and impactjs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pair with more hacker schoolers!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/21/hacker-school-day-12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/21/hacker-school-day-12.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 8</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to the feeling of being overwhelmed and not entirely sure what to do. But I’ve been told that this is normal and temporary, so I think everything will be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that although I really like the material in the Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, it wasn’t what I wanted to be focusing on (at least not at the pace things were going) so I decided to put that aside for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I made an analogue RGB clock. Today I reviewed it with Tom, a facilitator, and we improved the color arc functionality as well as developped a method for calculating the segments of time lengths that overlap in a generic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot; class=&quot;jscanvas&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;/Scripts/rgbclock.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Working with Tanoy on a music visualizer in Elm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue working on JavaScript stuff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/15/hacker-school-day-8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/15/hacker-school-day-8.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My first week at Hacker School went by in a blur. I spent a lot of time reading Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, programming in Scheme, learning Elm, reading a bit of Javascript, and attending talks on recursion, fundamentals of data structures and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also went to a few social things including happy hour at a “post-colonial British outpost in Jamaica” themed bar, and demo Thursday where I learned about max recursion depth in Python, and how Pokemon graphics are encrypted using Z-order curves. Oh, and I got to witness a blog being set up in 5 minutes to a rap song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still feeling a bit all over the place, but am doing alright. My biggest concern is SICP taking up too much of my time, so I might have to drop that for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue meeting people and asking what they&#39;re working on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pair programming with Victor today on the Pair Programming Roulette (so meta)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Monday Night Talk at eBay tonight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/13/hacker-school-day-6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/13/hacker-school-day-6.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Heart Swipe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Hacker School is keeping me extremely busy. I think it’ll be best not to pressure myself on this Processing challenge, so I hope this heart swipe will tide things over until I have time to make things again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas data-processing-sources=&quot;/Scripts/HeartSwipe.pde&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;[Challenge: Make and post 100 Processing sketches]&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 19:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/10/10/heart-swipe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/processing/2014/10/10/heart-swipe.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>processing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another long and busy day. First thing this morning I managed to get my practice JavaScript calculator working, so yay (it turned out to be just a syntax error - alas!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be perfectly honest, today was a bit frustrating. I wanted to do on a project in JavaScript and talked to facilitator &lt;a href=&quot;http://maryrosecook.com/&quot;&gt;Mary Rose Cook&lt;/a&gt; for advice on where to start. She suggested taking a game I had written in Python and doing it in JS, so I started on that. And then a few hours in regretted it and don’t want to finish it (figuring out console input is no fun at all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But. I met some more cool people, and went to a talk on recursion held by facilitator Alan O’Donnell which was pretty great and had all the mathy feels. I do know someone who is interested in writing a music visualization in Elm, and I meant to try to talk to them today but I got shy - so I will try to do that tomorrow. And we have our school photos out and mine didn’t turn out terrible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will keep powering through, and try not to get discouraged even if I feel like I still don’t know what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs first meetup tomorrow (and I&#39;m leading an exercise!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue meeting people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Continue scouting out other group projects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Happy hour tomorrow evening&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img style=&quot;width:200px;&quot; src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-07-hacker-school-day-1/HackerSchoolPhoto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/07/hacker-school-day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/07/hacker-school-day-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day 0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, my first day. Wow. I met a ton of incredibly interesting, friendly, genuine people. The space is an incredible environment, teeming with energetic hacker schoolers eager to work and learn and asking questions and having conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the day flew by in introductions, group discussions about what we were excited about and nervous about, lunch in China Town (where you can get dumplings for $3) and a couple of hours coding. I spent some time reading about JavaScript and coding along to make a terrible loan calculator, just to get the feel of a working client-side JS application (even though I can’t seem to get it working yet due to what I believe is the canvas element not being recognized.) In the evening I attended the Monday night talk held at eBay offices where &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cristina_Lopes&quot;&gt;Cristina Lopes&lt;/a&gt; talked about her book Exercises in Programming Style and the idea of abstracting style in programming. In her book she writes a simple program in 33 different styles; her talk tonight covered only a handful of them but the overall idea of identifying constraints that define a style, being aware of a variety of these styles and not getting stuck in any one type, was very clear. I also learned more about some new-to-me styles of programming using call-backs and concurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-07-hacker-school-day-0/hacker-school.png&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflective Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;I think I let my social anxiety get the better part of me at times, but I tried my best to be myself. I just hope I didn&#39;t come off as quiet/aloof or anxious/spastic. Anyways, I tried to roll with it, and in the future I will be mindful of that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs reading group starts tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;I would like to meet more people (go outside my comfort zone on this!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scout out other group projects and join one if it sounds like a cool project.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-07-hacker-school-day-0/hackers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption&gt;Goal: hack the planet&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 19:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/06/hacker-school-day-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/06/hacker-school-day-0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School Day -1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s the day before my first day at Hacker School, so I thought that I would try to get the blog ball rolling before I inevitably become busy and fall behind on it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m all settled into my new place in Brooklyn with former Hacker Schooler Jeff Fowler and roommate yet to be met Yuri. Both are musicians turned programmers, and I feel quite at home. The apartment is also beautiful with a large livingroom and kitchen area and lots of natural light; It also featues a piano (well, technically a weighted keyboard, but it’s quite nice) and whirltub bath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-05-hacker-school-day--1/livingroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption&gt;A peek into my new livingroom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been settling in days - unpacking, figuring out cell phone stuff, buying groceries etc. I’ve also been reading and coding, mostly the wizard manual &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/&quot;&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/a&gt; after hearing that there is a reading group starting up about it. I’ve read through Chapter 1.1, The Elements of Programming, and I think it’s great so far. It feels like lambda calculus (which makes perfect sense) but it’s extra nice to get to program everything while you learn (this book uses the Scheme dialect of Lisp).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-05-hacker-school-day--1/SICP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption&gt;Another perk of the new place - SICP is already on the bookshelf&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Things: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&#39;m still undecided about what I should work on at Hacker School, but am currently leaning towards diving into JavaScript (even though it&#39;s been a while and I need to seriously review) and making a game.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tonight I am attending an informal dinner get-together with the women (and anyone who identifies as a woman) of Hacker School. I think it&#39;ll be like a warm up to the first day of school.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;I definitely need to start including some code in these blog posts, so I need to figure out formatting that. I&#39;ll probably test the waters with SICP first.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/2014-10-05-hacker-school-day--1/touchdown.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;missing&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption&gt;Touch down - prepare to be glitched NY&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/05/hacker-school-day--1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/hackerschool/2014/10/05/hacker-school-day--1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>hackerschool</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New York Here I Come</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sitting in an airport waiting for a flight that will take me to New York City. And it still hasn’t sunk in that I will be spending the next three months learning and coding at Hacker School. I have a few ideas for projects I’d like to work on, but at the moment I’m feeling like getting a solid grounding in Python might be a good first step. I do want to make some games and graphics and visualization stuff. It is all very undecided and terrifying, but also exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/PostImages/NewYork.png&quot; alt=&quot;Artistic Rendition of New York City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main objective at the moment is to get focused on something. I’m afraid I’ve been terribly unsure about everything so far and keep jumping around as a result. Other objectives include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;blogging regularly (even if I cringe at my own writing sometimes)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;talk to people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;power through self-doubt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;make time to not stress about things or feel like I should be working&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/10/02/new-york-here-i-come.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://juliatufts.com/blog/2014/10/02/new-york-here-i-come.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
